Lin Qi fears rats the most.
林七这个人啊 最怕老鼠了
So I put 27 rats into her chamber.
把她跟二十七只老鼠放在一起
I'll see what she will look like tomorrow.
我看她明天出来什么脸色
She wanted to beat me?
打我
Lin Qi is no match for me at all.
她林七根本就不是我的对手
I will scare her to death.
吓死她
How do you feel now? Are you still angry?
怎么样 消气了没
It is avenging you on her,
不是替你报仇吗
not me.
怎么就成我消气了
It was a competition.
这 这本来就是比武嘛
We have signed a disclaimer.
签了生死状的
We can't seek revenge.
哪有去寻仇的道理
I don't like fighting and killing.
不要随便打打杀杀的
Your Highness is so kind.
我们三公主好善良啊
Kind?
善良
I'd rather say Her Highness is so mean.
你们三公主这招真够损的
I caught 27 rats for her.
一下子抓了二十七只老鼠
It made me exhausted.
累死我了
At least Her Highness is kinder
那也总比你们家少君那么狠
than Young Master Han.
好多了
Young Master Han and the Third Princess,
我们少君跟你们三公主
one is ruthless and the other is mean.
一个狠 一个损
They are well matched.
般配
Zi Rui. Let's go.
梓锐 咱们走
OK.
好
It is my negligence.
是属下疏忽
There is an escaped...rat.
居然有漏网之鱼 之鼠
Hey, take it away
你给我
from me, Bai Ji.
你 你给我拿远点 白芨
Farther away.
再远点
Go. Zi Rui. Go.
走走走 梓锐 走走走
Young Master.
少君
Please give me a chance to make up for my mistake.
请给属下一个将功补过的机会吧
Not necessary.
不必了
I will reward you.
本少君要重重赏你
But...
那个
The third test. Discourse on politics.
第三试 策论
This time, the question is about current politics.
此次 策论的试题谈谈时政
Now, in Huayuan City,
如今我花垣城
the silver reserve is decreasing and financial condition is bad.
存银减少 财政欠佳
Would you please tell me
各位说说
if you have any good advice on increasing revenue?
有没有增收的良策
Mother, I have a piece of good advice.
母亲 我有一良策
Tell me.
说
We could increase head tax.
不如 增收人丁税
First, this tax can guarantee financial income.
一来 可以保障财政收入
Second, it can control population,
二来 可以调整控制人口
so that population will not increase too quickly
避免人口过重
and become a burden on the economy.
缓解人口压力
As far as I know,
据我所知
Huayuan City has a total population of 150,000,
花垣城总人口为十五万人
in which 105,000 are adults.
其中成年人为十万五千人
If every adult
若是每一个成年人
pays 120 qians of silver for head tax every year,
每年交纳人丁税一百二十钱
our income will increase a lot every year.
一年又有多少两银子的收入
If they do not have silver,
若是没有银子的话
they also can pay the tax with grain.
也可以拿粮食置换
In that case,
这样的话
our grain will also increase a lot.
又能储存多少粮食
They are necessary for unexpected needs.
以备不时之需
Well.
不是
Is there anyone
就没有一个算数好的
who can calculate it for me?
帮我算一下吗
Minister Liu, what do you say?
刘司银 你说呢
105,000 people.
十万五千人
Everyone pays 120 qians of silver every year.
每人每年一百二十钱
1,000 qians is equal to one tael.
一千钱为一两
It can be exchanged for 200 dous of rice.
可换二百斗米
It means...
也就是
Your Majesty.
启禀城主
It means an increase of 100,000 taels of silver
一年便是上万两白银
or millions of dous of rice.
数百万斗米
I never thought that the Third Princess was so brilliant.
想不到三公主竟有如此头脑
If such amount of income is increased every year,
若每年有如此多的增收
the difficulties Huayuan City is facing now
那将直接解决
will be overcome.
我们花垣城眼下的困境
Brilliant. Brilliant.
佩服 佩服
Her Highness is a governing talent.
三公主经世良才
It is a blessing for Huayuan City.
是我花垣城之幸
Wait.
等等
Your Highness. Something seems to be wrong.
三公主 不对吧
Does Minister Liu have a question?
刘司银有何不满
Huayuan City has a total population of 150,000,
我花垣城总人口十五万
in which 105,000 are adults.
成年人十万五千人
Your Highness.
三公主
Have you included men in the calculation?
莫不是把成年男子也算进去了
Of course.
当然了
Men and women
成年男子跟成年女子
are all adults.
都是成年人
They all should pay the tax.
当然要一起纳税了
It seems that the Third Princess's knowledge of political affairs
三公主果然不如二郡主
is not as good as the Second Princess.
关心政事啊
In Huayuan City,
我花垣城
people who pay tax should enjoy relevant rights.
纳税义务与享用权利相应
If women pay tax, their social status will be higher than that of men.
女子纳税则以女子为尊
If men also pay tax,
如若男子一同纳税
doesn't it mean that we have admitted the rights of men?
那岂不是直接承认了男子的权利
By that time,
到时候
men will be officials and businessmen.
男子为官 男子经商
They will have the same social status with women.
与女子平起平坐
The Third Princess is trying to set a trap for Her Majesty.
这三公主不是来给城主下圈套吗
If men pay tax, they will become heads of households.
纳税岂不是给男子开了户籍
That is unacceptable.
那还不反了天了
If men have rights,
男子有了权利
what will become of Huayuan City?
这花垣城还像什么样子
Its foundation will be damaged.
简直是乱了根本
If that is so,
照这样下去
we may as well change the name of Huayuan City into Xuanhu City.
我们花垣城改成玄虎城好了
Did the Third Princess have her brain damaged
这三公主该不会是武试的时候
in the Kung Fu test?
脑壳被打坏了吧
It is not easy to win,
想赢不容易
but it is easy to loss.
想输还不好说吗
Qianqian.
芊芊
You are a princess of Huayuan City,
你身为花垣城郡主
but you disregard the dignity of our ancestors.
完全不顾祖宗的体面
It is disgraceful.
成何体统
Mother.
母亲
I am too naive.
童言无忌 童言无忌
Please still consider me to be a baby.
你就当我还是个宝宝
Sorry for my childish words.
说错话了
It is OK.
罢了
Since Qianqian is still a baby,
看在芊芊还是个宝宝的分儿上
let's not talk about it anymore.
此事 过了
Baby?
还是个宝宝呢
Next.
下一位
I have a piece of advice.
女儿有一计策
Xuanhu City makes black stones into bombs,
玄虎城将乌石制成炸药
while Huayuan City makes black stones into fireworks.
而花垣城将乌石制成烟花
Your Highness. Look.
三公主 你看
These are clothes and jewelry.
穿的 戴的
They are at a standard equal to those for the Crown Princess.
通通是少城主的规格
Later, when I give these presents to Chuchu,
一会儿楚楚看到我送她礼物
she will be very happy.
一定会特别地开心
Congratulations! Chuchu.
恭喜二姐
Now you are the winner of the discourse on politics.
策论魁首
Congratulations to you. You are the winner of the Kung Fu test.
恭喜三妹 武试魁首
You know that I won the Kung Fu test
你也知道我那武试赢的
with some tactics.
不是那么光彩
When the results of the literacy test come out,
等文试成绩一出来
you will be
少城主之位
the Crown Princess.
可就尽收囊中了
Look.
你看
I have prepared presents for you.
贺礼我都给你准备好了
We only need to wait for mother's order of coronation.
就等母亲下令册封了
Presents?
贺礼
For me?
送我的
Chuchu, think about my bet.
二姐 想想我的赌注
I will become rich because of you.
可就是靠你发家致富了
How is your wound?
你的伤怎么样了
I have been preparing for the discourse test these days.
这些天我在准备策论
I didn't have time to see you.
都没来得及去看你
It doesn't matter. It is a small wound.
没事 小伤
It has been cured by the medicine given by Yuanyuan.
长姐给我的药早就擦好了
Following the god's will,
顺应天命
we hereby announce the results of the Crown Princess Election.
少城主擢考结果如下
The winner of the first place in the discourse on politics
策论甲等
is the Second Princess Chen Chuchu.
二郡主 陈楚楚
The winner of the first place in the Kung Fu test
武试甲等
is the Third Princess Chen Qianqian.
三郡主 陈芊芊
Without me,
陈芊芊能赢
Chen Qianqian couldn't win.
还不是都靠我
The winner of the first place in the literacy test
文试甲等
The winner...
文
Your Majesty. This...
城主 这
The winner of the first place in the literacy test
文试甲等
is the Third Princess Chen Qianqian.
三郡主 陈芊芊
It is her.
是她
How could she win the first place?
她怎么得第一呀
This
这
is ridiculous.
太不可思议了
How strange!
怎么会这样
The literacy test...I am the winner?
文试 我
Congratulations to Your Highness.
恭喜三郡主
Am I the winner?
老丁头赢了
The Third Princess Chen Qianqian
三郡主陈芊芊
has brilliant literary ability
文采斐然
and excellent Kung Fu skills.
武艺绝伦
She is also a governing talent.
有经世之才
She is capable of shouldering great responsibilities.
堪当大任
Therefore, she is conferred the title of Crown Princess,
故册封少城主
in order to make the city more prosperous and protect Huayuan City.
以兹城邦 保佑花垣
Mother.
母亲
I am not suitable.
我不适合
I can't be the Crown Princess.
我不能做少城主
Qianqian.
芊芊
You have been intelligent and diligent since childhood.
你自小懂事 努力上进
I always have great expectations for you.
我对你一直寄予厚望
You have won the election,
此事是你历经考核
you should be the Crown Princess.
考出来的少城主
Why do you refuse?
你为何要推辞
I have neither talent nor virtue.
女儿无才无德
Chuchu...
没有
Chuchu is more suitable to be the Crown Princess.
没有二姐适合当少城主
Please let Chuchu be the Crown Princess.
让二姐来当吧
I am not good enough.
我真的不行
Chuchu. Do you agree?
楚楚 是吗
Qianqian has been intelligent since childhood.
芊芊自幼聪慧
I am willing to assist her.
女儿愿辅佐三妹
I will be faithful to her.
忠心不二
No. No.
不不不 不行不行不行
It is settled.
就这么定了
Qianqian. Go back home and prepare for the coronation.
芊芊 回去准备册封礼吧
I am tired after a few busy days.
折腾了几天 我也累了
Mother. No.
母亲 不是
Mother.
母亲
Dismiss.
都散了吧
Mother! No! Mother!
母亲 不是 母亲
Mother. Chuchu. Chuchu.
母亲 楚楚 楚楚
Chuchu. Chuchu.
楚楚 楚楚 楚楚
Please don't go. Please don't go.
你别走 你别走
Your highness.
三公主
Please don't go.
你别走
All is ready.
东西一直备着呢
What are Your Highness trying to explain?
三公主还解释什么呀
You have prepared everything for yourself.
东西都自己备好了
Don't pretend to be kind.
还跟这儿假客气
Chuchu.
二姐
Congratulations to you.
恭喜三妹
Now you are the Crown Princess.
获封少城主
Chuchu.
二姐
The Third Princess.
三公主 那
No, I mean Crown Princess.
不 少城主
Now you have won the whole Huayuan City.
如今已经赢了整个花垣城
Why are you still not happy?
你还有什么不开心的
It seems that I have won the whole city,
你们看着我是赢了整座城
but actually I have lost the whole world.
实际上我是输了全世界
Completely.
彻头彻尾
I have lost all my fortune.
倾家荡产
No.
不是
Why did I win?
我怎么就赢了呢
You said I would lose if I stuck to what I like.
说好了我做自己就能输嘛
What should I do?
我现在该怎么办
Why are you dressed like this?
不是 你们怎么穿成这样
Right. You also bet that Chuchu would win.
对 你们也押了楚楚赢
Didn't you also bet on the Second Princess?
你自己不也押二郡主赢吗
You...
她 你
Dismiss.
散了 散了
You are useless.
我要你们有什么用啊
Nothing has been done and money is gone.
事没做成 钱也没留住
And I have to tell stories to you every day.
我还每天还给你们讲故事
You. You...
你们 你们
You are the so-called braggers.
你们就是那种 那种喷子
You do nothing except
那种不干实事 只靠嘴说的
bragging.
那种喷子
Your Highness. Please don't discard us.
公主 你不要抛弃我们嘛
Yes.
对 那个
We still don't understand the relationship
香蕉 橙子 还有苹果那关系
among banana, orange and apple.
都还没捋清呢 不是吗 对吧
If we don't listen to your stories for one day,
我们现在一天不听更新呀
we will feel agitated.
就抓心挠肝
I will stop the project of banana, orange and apple.
橙子苹果香蕉项目我不做了
I can't afford you anymore.
我养不起你们了
The relations of characters are a mess. I am done with it.
人物关系乱套了 做什么做
Minister Pei.
司学
Do you want to see how miserable I am?
你是来看我笑话的吧
I know that you are a proud lady.
我知道你要强
It is not strange
这次落败
that you feel upset about your defeat.
心中难免不甘
I am here to comfort you.
特来劝你
Yes.
是啊
I have worked hard since I was a child.
我从小努力
But my mother's most favorite daughter
可在母亲眼里
is always Qianqian.
最讨喜的永远是芊芊
She blatantly played tricks in the Kung Fu test,
她明目张胆耍赖
but mother judged that she won.
母亲却判她赢武试
She acted wildly and talked nonsense in the hall,
她当堂撒野 大放厥词
but mother was reluctant to punish her.
母亲却不忍责罚
No matter how hard I work,
我做再多
I won't be appreciated by mother.
都得不到母亲的赞赏
Even though Qianqian is mischievous,
芊芊胡闹
she is adored by my mother.
却可以深得宠爱
I am also a daughter of my mother.
同样为人女
Why does she treat us differently?
为何我与她如此不同
She who loves well chastises well.
爱之深 责之切
Maybe Her Majesty
或许城主
has higher expectations for you.
恰是对你有更高的期望
That's why she is stricter with you.
才会对你有更加苛刻的要求吧
Higher expectations?
更高的期望
In the past, I would believe these words.
这话放在以前我还信
But now,
可现在
mother has conferred her the title of Crown Princess.
母亲连少城主之位也给了她
I am not well today.
我今天身体不适
Sorry for the snub.
多有怠慢
Please take care.
二郡主保重
Crown Princess said
少城主说什么
that she bet all her money on you.
押了全部身家在您身上
But do you know
可您知道吗
that Young Master Han bet all his money
韩少君早就将全部身家
on the Crown Princess.
押了少城主赢
He has earned a lot of money.
现如今赚得盆满钵满
They were just playing tricks.
他们两口子是左手倒右手
Your Highness have been deceived.
忽悠您玩呢
Are you sure?
你说的可是真的
Money have been sent to Yueli Mansion.
金银珠宝都送到月璃府去了
Please don't be angry, Your Highness.
郡主息怒
It is my fault.
怪我
I underestimated Chen Qianqian.
竟然小看了陈芊芊
I won't believe a word of what she says in future.
日后她说什么我都不会再信了
Why did you ask me to come here?
叫我来干什么
Young Master bet a lot of money
我们少君特意花重金下注
that Your Highness would win the title of Crown Princess.
赌三公主您能荣登城主之位
He wanted to give you a surprise.
想给您一个惊喜
He never expected that
万万没想到的是
the odds were so high.
这茶馆的赔率实在是太大了
Let me put it this way:
就这么跟你说吧
now our mansion
现在我们府上
is the biggest winner in the whole Huayuan City.
是整个花垣城最大的赢家
What do you mean?
什么意思
Is my money back?
我的钱回来了
Actually,
准确地说呢
we should say that your money
应该是你的钱
was spent by you
从你手上给花出去了
and then earned back by me.
又从我手上给赚回来了
During the process,
顺便
I also earned some interest.
给你挣了点利息
So it's you that helped me win the literacy test.
原来是你帮我赢了文试
Please don't thank me.
不用谢我
I said that
我说过
I will give you what you want.
要给你想要的东西
You...
你
I...
我
You are coquettish.
汝甚骚
What does that mean?
什么意思
You are truly the Crown Prince of Xuanhu City.
不愧是玄虎城少城主啊
You're so dense.
你太虎了
What does "dense" mean?
虎是什么意思
It means handsome.
夸你帅呢
But I think you are mad at me.
我怎么觉得你有点生气啊
Do you know that you are a danger to your wife?
你克妻 你知不知道
I...
我
I never said that I wanted to be the Crown Princess.
谁说要当少城主的
But...
不是
I have heard for a long time that the Third Princess is capricious.
久闻三公主任性
Now I know it is true.
今天我算是领教了
I helped you to win the title of Crown Princess.
不知道我为你筹谋少城主之位
I don't know what's wrong with it.
有什么不好的
Before you give me anything,
你给我什么东西之前
can you ask me if I like it?
能不能问我喜不喜欢 想不想要
How could you not like
我送你的东西
what I sent you?
你怎么会不喜欢
Your Highness.
三公主
Auspicious clothes for the parade have arrived.
游街的吉服已经送过来了
I don't want to be the Crown Princess,
少城主我是真不想当
but this dress is so beautiful.
这衣服是真好看
Your Highness. This ceremonial dress
少城主 你这件礼服
is made of fine silk fabrics.
可是用上好的绸缎制成的
It is very expensive.
金贵得很哪
You will ride a horse on the street,
一会儿打马游街
offer sacrifices to heaven at the ancestral temple, and meet Her Majesty.
祠堂祭天 面见城主
You will be the most magnificent
您是花垣建城以来
Crown Princess of Huayuan City ever.
最耀眼的少城主
Why do I have to parade, offer sacrifices and bow again?
怎么又是游街 祭天 拜堂
They were all exempted when I got married.
成亲的时候都免了
Can't we get away with them this time?
这次不能一起免了吗
Why did he come?
他怎么来了
He is your husband, isn't he?
人家好歹也是你的夫婿不是
According to the ancestral rules,
依祖制
you should attend the coronation ceremony together.
你俩要一起完成受 受封礼
You...
你
You see. Her Highness
你说你们少城主啊
is ungrateful.
捡了便宜还卖乖
Young Master actually did it for the good of her.
我们少君明明就是为了她好
Her Highness didn't need his help.
我们少城主才不稀罕呢
Let me tell you.
我告诉你啊
A right present is a surprise.
送礼送对了 那叫惊喜
A wrong present is a scare.
送错了 那叫惊吓
Do you know what love is?
懂不懂什么叫感情
You sound like you understand it.
说得就好像你懂似的
Of course I understand.
我当然懂了
Whatever I do,
无论我做什么
I do it for the good of Her Highness.
都是为了我们少城主好
Yes, it is true.
是为了你们少城主好
But you are a little stupid.
可你就是笨了点
You made 500 bamboo tubes,
一下子做了五百个火漆竹筒
as if you were afraid that others could not find out.
生怕别人发现不了
You
你这人
just like talking about others' weakness.
你怎么哪壶不开你提哪壶啊
Don't think that I don't know it.
你别以为我不知道啊
On the day of bridegroom snatching, you wanted to trap the Second Princess,
抢亲那天就是你设计二郡主
but in the end you trapped Her Highness.
结果反套住了我们三郡主
You are unable to accomplish anything.
你个成事不足
You are liable to spoil everything.
你败事有余
the Third Princess is coming.
三公主来了 三公主
Since you didn't like it,
你若是不喜欢
why didn't you tell me earlier?
为何不早同我说
I just never expected that you would come up with such a big plan.
只是没想到你有这么大的主意
You even interfered in the succession affair.
连继任城主之事都要插手
Since ancient times, as long as power struggle has been involved,
自古以来只要涉及到权力之争
it has always meant life and death.
就是你死我活
Do you know that someone behind you
你知不知道你背后
may set you up?
可能有人正在算计你
If you don't fight,
你不争
you will get a blow and face numerous disasters.
就是一败涂地 死劫重重
Let's not talk about anything else.
别的先不说
Isn't my disaster sitting beside me?
我的死劫不就坐在我面前吗
We are a couple.
你我好歹夫妻一场
How could I harm you?
我怎么可能会害你
Are we a couple?
夫妻
Have we worshiped Heaven?
祭天了吗
Have we slept together?
洞房了吗
Have we bowed to Heaven and Earth?
拜堂了吗
Have we paraded?
游街了吗
Aren't we parading now?
咱们不是正在游街吗
Later, we will worship Heaven.
一会儿就去祭天
If you are not satisfied,
如果三公主不满意的话
We can bow to Heaven and Earth later.
我们晚些可以重新拜堂
If that is not enough, we can
如果还不够 也可以
sleep together.
洞房
In your dreams.
想得倒挺美
Stop the cart.
停车
Why did the cart stop?
怎么停车了呀
Your Highness.
少城主
You...
你
Do you think that we are not a couple
你是不是觉得与我成亲
because we haven't completed the marriage ceremony?
是未完之礼
Without bowing to Heaven and Earth, worshiping Heaven, and parading.
没有拜堂 祭天 游街
You are also trying to ruin this parade.
想方设法要把这次游街也破坏掉
Excuse me. It is you who stopped the cart.
拜托 是你叫停的花车
If Your Highness doesn't want to parade with me,
三公主既然不愿与韩某游街
I shall leave.
韩某告退
Han Shuo. Sorry. That is not what I meant.
韩烁 对不起 我不是这个意思
I...
我
Han Shuo. Stop.
韩烁 你给我站住
Han Shuo. I think you misunderstood me.
韩烁 我不是那个意思
I really don't want to be the Crown Princess.
我是真的不想当少城主
On the day when you were poisoned,
那日三公主中毒之后
you said
可是亲口说的
you were crying all day
失去了竞选少城主的资格
after losing the qualification for attending Crown Princess Election.
整日以泪洗面
Now you said you didn't want to be the Crown Princess.
现在又说自己不想当少城主
I really don't know
三公主的心思果然如同海底针
what's on your mind.
难猜得紧
Fortunately, I have recovered from the heart disease.
亏得韩某心疾痊愈
Otherwise,
否则今日
I would die today.
就是我绝命之时
Yes.
对
I have cured your heart disease.
心疾我帮你治好的
I cured you with Dragon Bone.
我拿龙骨帮你治好的
You took Dragon Bone just because you felt guilty.
你拿龙骨是因为愧疚
You falsely accused me of communicating with the spy of Xuanhu City.
你陷害我与玄虎密探私通
I was almost killed by the Second Princess.
我差点被二郡主剿灭
That was because I was afraid of you.
那我不是因为怕你吗
In the past, you looked like a tiger eyeing its prey.
再说 是谁之前虎视眈眈的
When I was in Yueli Mansion,
我在月璃府
I haven't had a good meal.
连一顿饭都没有好好吃过
When I faced a table of glazed plates,
一桌的琉璃盏啊
I felt like I was drawing lots.
我吃个饭跟抽签似的
Your Highness was so cautious.
三公主对韩某防范得紧啊
Do you have any secret?
莫不是有什么亏心事
The thing happened in the Music and Dance Academy
教坊司的事
was a humiliation to me. I was embarrassed in public.
我可是颜面扫地 当街出丑
Why do you only hold grudges?
怎么就记得人坏
Do you forget what I did good for you?
不记得人好了呢
Do you remember I lied that I was pregnant
我不是还 谎称有孕
and saved you from the death row.
把你从死牢里救了出来
The way I treated you...
我对你
Why was I in prison?
我因何入狱呀
Wasn't it you who set me up?
难道不是三公主陷害的吗
In the past,
之前
we weren't getting along well with each other,
我们不是相处得不太融洽吗
were we?
对吧
I thought that you were going to poison me.
我以为你要下毒害我
You forced me to be your husband on the street.
你自己当街抢的亲 当街
On the street.
当街抢亲
On this very street.
就这条街
Yes.
对
You forced me to marry you.
自己当街抢亲
Otherwise, I would not poison you in the bridal chamber.
不然哪有洞房下毒这事
You are shameless to say that.
那你还有脸说
I...
我
Why did I force you to marry me?
我为什么要抢亲啊
Because you seduced me.
那不是你色诱我吗
Besides, I know that
再说了 你以为我不知道
the person you wanted to save was not me, but Chuchu.
你想救的人不是我 是楚楚
Young Master. It is our fault in this case.
少君 这段咱们理亏
How did she know?
她怎么知道这事的
I don't know.
我也不知道
I am the Young Master of Xuanhu.
我堂堂玄虎少君
How can I quarrel with a woman in the street?
竟然与一妇人当街争吵
Woman?
妇人
What's wrong with woman?
妇人怎么了
Please don't talk to me in that discriminatory language.
你别用这种性别歧视的语气
Let me tell you.
跟我说话 我告诉你
In this world, only men and villains
这世间 唯有男子跟小人
are hard to get along with.
难养也
Since you don't want me to parade with you,
三公主既然不喜韩某同行
Please parade by yourself.
您就 自己去游街吧
Fine.
自己游就自己游
Dress. Dress.
衣服 衣服
Wha...
这
What is going on?
这是什么新的彩头
This is ridiculous.
岂有此理
Han Shuo is tearing Qianqian's dress
大庭广众之下
in public
韩烁竟然损毁芊芊衣物
to humiliate his wife.
当众羞辱妻子
The men of Xuanhu City really don't respect their wives.
玄虎城男子果然不敬妻子
They don't know how to sever women and are unfaithful.
不会伺候 不安于室
He is not good enough for Qianqian.
根本就配不上芊芊
What are you looking at?
看看看 看什么 看看看
Han Shuo. Han Shuo. Don't go.
韩烁 韩烁 你别走
Han Shuo. I hate you.
韩烁 我跟你势不两立
It seems that the Crown Princess doesn't like Young Master Han.
我看这少城主根本不喜欢韩少君
Qianqian spends time in the Music and Dance Academy every evening.
芊芊夜夜流连于教坊司
When it comes to love affairs,
男女之情于她而言
she only fancies something new.
不过是一时新鲜
Han Shuo is so pathetic.
倒可惜了韩烁
He loves her so much.
对她一往情深
As far as I am concerned,
依小的看
Your Highness is a natural fit with Young Master Han.
您和韩少君才是天作之合
Though the Crown Princess kidnapped the bridegroom,
少城主虽半路抢亲
she will return him back eventually.
但最终 还是会物归原主的
I was stripped off clothes in the parade.
这游街的时候被扒了衣服
What should it be called?
这算什么
The Emperor's New Clothes.
皇帝的新衣
It is disgraceful.
太丢人了
Your Highness. Please don't angry.
三公主消消气啊
Would you like to have an orange?
来 扒个橙子吃
Peel the orange?
扒橙子
That's bad luck. Peel a banana.
晦气 扒根香蕉
Yes.
好
Young Master.
我说少君
Luckily you walked on the street.
你幸好是用腿走的
If I gave you a horse,
我给你一匹马
wouldn't you have dragged me
你是不是还得拖着我
all the way down the street?
走完整个大街啊
I don't want to see the bana...
我以后再也不想看到你这只香
you anymore.
你这个人了
Your Highness.
少城主
What is this?
这什么呀
Now you are the Crown Princess.
现在身为少城主
You need to help Her Majesty to handle the government affairs.
要主动帮城主分担政务
Doesn't the Crown Princess have an internship period?
不是 少城主就没有个实习期吗
If I have to handle so much work in the beginning,
一上来就这么多工作
I will be stressed out.
我压力很大的
When the Crown Princess paraded on the street, she took off her clothes. She disregarded...
少城主游街当众脱衣 罔顾
Is this an official document?
这是公文吗
This is a tabloid.
这就是八卦杂志
All are nonsense.
都是瞎写的
If you feel angry, please don't read it.
看了生气就别看了
No.
别看了
Young Master. Listen carefully.
少君可得听好了
When the Crown Princess paraded on the street, she took off her clothes.
少城主游街 当众脱衣
She disregarded ancestral etiquette.
罔顾祖宗之礼法
What she did is disgraceful
不知羞耻
and disgusting.
不堪入目
She even frolicked with Young Master on the street.
更是与少君当街嬉戏
They chased one another,
打闹追逐
blatantly flirting on the street.
将闺房之乐置于大街之上
Their conducts made people annoyed.
引人唾弃
Her Highness read it so aloud
念得掷地有声
as if it had nothing to do with her.
仿佛上面写的不是她一样
Keep your big mouth shut!
让你说我们少城主
Shut up.
让你说
I don't want to see you again.
我 再也不想看到你了
Bandits on the Weimeng Mountain often harass traveling merchants.
今威猛山山匪骚扰商队
the Crown Princess should lead the City Guards to suppress bandits.
少城主应率领护城军剿匪
What is this about?
这什么跟什么呀
If you want, you can go there. I won't do it.
要去你去 我可不去
This is my room.
这是我房间
You should leave.
要走也是你走吧
This is the soup that I sent to the Crown Princess.
特意给少城主送去的汤
Why has it been sent back?
怎么又送回来了
Her Highness said that
那个 少城主说
your soup tastes awful.
少君的汤 噎得慌
She wanted you to drink it yourself.
让您自己喝
Young Master. Don't be angry.
少君 您别生气呀
Am I angry?
我生气了吗
It is she who is angry with me.
现在是少城主在生我的气
I don't dare to be angry with her.
我哪敢生少城主的气呀
Bai Ji.
白芨
Do you think that I am angry?
你说我生气了吗
Young Master.
少君
You have read a lot of books on the art of war since childhood.
您说您从小就熟读兵法
You know a lot of strategies.
各种计谋是烂熟于心
Is there any strategy that
就没有什么
you can use to tackle Her Highness?
能往三公主身上用用的吗
This is not about war.
这又不是上阵杀敌
Young Master.
少君
I have heard that
我听说
if a couple has disputes,
这夫妻之间闹别扭
one side should not talk first to the other side.
就得先晾着对方
The one who talks first is the loser.
谁先开口 谁先说话 谁就输了
I have a strategy.
要我说 咱们先来一计
You should ignore her.
别搭理她
Are you a spy sent by Pei Heng?
你是裴恒派来的吗
You misunderstood me.
不是
In the past, if someone offended you,
往日谁要是惹着您不开心
you would do the same thing
通常都是以其人之道
to that person.
还治其人之身
You have always been determined.
挺杀伐果断的
But when it comes to Her Highness,
怎么到了三公主这儿
you look indecisive.
就瞻前顾后的
Pay somebody back
以其人之道
in his own coin.
还治其人之身
I have an idea. Bai Ji.
有了 白芨
Listen to me.
你快去准备一下
Will it work?
这样行吗
Let us have a try.
姑且只能试一试了
Hurry up.
快去
Yes.
是
I shouldn't tear your dress
游街扯你裙子的事
during the parade.
算我不对
Now, you can tear my dress.
这次 你扯
When you walk, my dress will be stripped off.
你走 我就脱光了
You...
你
I will do what you said.
这可是你说的
You are boring.
真无聊
Your Highness. Minister Pei is coming.
三公主 裴司学来了
Chen Qianqian. Stop.
陈芊芊 你别跑了
Qianqian. What are you doing?
芊芊 你这是
Pei Heng.
裴恒
I was playing a game with my wife.
我正与夫人嬉闹
Please don't laugh at me.
见笑了
Young Master Han is really
韩少君真是
different from the men of Huayuan City.
与花垣城男子不同
Since you are in Huayuan City now,
既然少君身处花垣
you should get rid of
还是要改一改
the bad habits of the men of Huayuan City.
玄虎城男子身上的劣习
I...
我
(Men Virtues) Young Master Han
这本书
should read this book carefully.
韩少君好好学一学
Yes. Read it carefully.
好好学学啊
Ok. I will read it.
学就学
Pei Heng.
裴恒
You've come just at the right moment.
你来得可真是及时
I have received a lot of official documents
我有一大堆公文
and I don't know how to handle them.
我都不知道该怎么办呢
If you have time,
你以后要是没事的时候
can you come here to help me to handle government affairs?
天天来帮我处理政务好不好
In Huayuan City, women are rulers.
花垣城 女子当政
It is not suitable for men to interfere in government affairs.
男子插手 多有不便
It doesn't matter.
这有什么
You're not an outsider.
你又不是外人
Come on.
走吧
Handling official documents is not difficult.
批阅公文算什么
Young Master has been doing it since childhood.
我们少君从小批到大
Has Pei Heng left?
裴恒他还没走啊
No.
没有
There are just two of them in the room.
孤男寡女共处一室
What do they have to talk about?
他们到底有什么好聊的
Recently, Criminal Minister judged
司刑大人最近处决一例
a case of domestic violence crime committed by a blacksmith.
铁匠恶劣家庭暴力事件
Tie family.
铁家
A blacksmith from Jiang family.
蒋家铁匠
The housewife often beat her husband violently.
其妻子长期暴打丈夫
The husband sued for divorce many times but failed.
丈夫多次申诉和离无果
He eventually couldn't stand it anymore and beat his wife violently.
终于忍无可忍暴打妻子
His wife was shocked.
导致妻子心灵受到了冲击
She couldn't accept the reality of being beaten.
不能接受被打现实
According to the law of Huayuan City,
依花垣城法典
it is judged
做如下处罚
that the husband shall be torn apart by five horses.
判丈夫五马分尸
What is that?
这什么啊
Men and women are so unequal.
这 这男女也太不平等了吧
Why are men so vulnerable
这男子怎么在婚姻里
in marriage?
一点保障都没有啊
In Huayuan City,
在花垣
according to ancestral precepts,
男子三从四德
men should be obedient and obey virtue ethics.
是被写进祖训的
If a man beats his wife,
丈夫对妻子出手
he commits a severe crime.
是极重之罪
But that was too much.
那也不能这么过分啊
Men and women should respect each other
先不说男女在家庭婚姻中
in marriage life.
本来就应该互相尊重
Apart from that, men should have
单说男子在社会地位上
the same social status as you.
那也都应该像你一样
They shouldn't be treated differently because of gender.
不要因为性别而被区别对待
As for me,
我
I am just an exceptional case.
我不过是个特例
My status depends on the fame of my mother
凭借的是 我母亲
the late Minister Pei,
已故裴司军的威名
the affection from Her Majesty,
城主的宠爱
and the marriage contract with you.
还有你的婚约
No. No.
不不不
Don't think in that way.
你可千万别这么想
It is because of your talent
你能成为花垣城第一个男司学
that you became the first male minister in Huayuan City.
凭的是你的真才实学
In my mind,
在我心目里
you are a true man.
真正的男子就是这样的
You have talent but don't show off.
有才识又不外露
You treat people with gentleness and deal things with good sense.
待人温和 处事明理
Besides, you are handsome.
而且 还长得帅
I must say that you are a male god.
简直就是男神
Male god?
男 男神
How should I explain it?
怎么解释呢
It is like...
就是
When people meet you
让人接触到你
and see you,
看到你的时候
they will like you unconsciously.
就会 不自觉地喜欢上你
What's wrong? Why are you shy?
怎么了 害羞什么
Thank Your Highness for your affection.
谢少城主抬爱
No. No. Pei Heng.
不是不是 裴恒
You misunderstood me.
你理解错了
I didn't mean that.
不是那个意思
The like I just said
就是 我说的那个喜欢
is not the like
跟你想的那个喜欢
that you think.
它不是一种喜欢
The like that you think...
你想的那种喜欢
Qianqian.
芊芊
You don't have to explain.
你不必解释
I know.
我懂
You don't know.
你不太懂
Young Master. What's wrong with you?
少君 你怎么了
Does your heart disease recur?
是不是心疾又犯了
I feel a little uncomfortable.
略堵
It's OK.
无妨
I just asked Her Highness.
属下刚刚打听过了
I was told that there are a lot of government affairs.
花垣城政务繁重
They have been working till now.
他们一直忙到现在
the Crown Princess is afraid that it is too late for Minister Pei
少城主担心裴司学回去太晚
to go home,
不安全
so she asked servants
就吩咐下人
to arrange accommodation for him.
安排他在这儿住下了
It turns out that I was busy for nothing.
原来我白忙一场
I helped her to be the Crown Princess.
将她拱上少城主之位
She never thanked me for that.
不但没得她一句感谢
Besides, Pei Heng also found an excuse to approach Qianqian.
反叫裴恒有机可乘
Young Master.
少君
Isn't it like bringing a wolf into the house?
这不是引狼入室吗
Don't blame me for using some strategies.
那就别怪我釜底抽薪了
Suppressing bandits in Weimeng Mountain
威猛山剿匪之事
(City Owner's Mansion) should be under Crown Princess's charge.
非少城主莫属
the Crown Princess just took office.
少城主刚刚任职
It is time for her to make some achievements.
正是建功立业的时候
But Her highness has lost all her Kung Fu.
可少城主武功尽失
I am afraid that it's dangerous for her to lead the army.
独自带军恐有危险
I think
依我看
we had better send the Second Princess to Weimeng Mountain.
不如 派二郡主
In that case, the Crown Princess can go with Young Master Han.
那就让少城主带上韩少君
Young Master Han is highly skilled in Kung Fu.
韩少君武艺高强
He is capable enough to protect Her Highness.
足以保护少城主
Then, they will quarrel all the way
然后两人一路内讧
to Weimeng Mountain.
直到威猛山
Do you think the parade case
此前游街一事
is not disgraceful enough?
难道还不够丢脸吗
It is not strange that a couple would quarrel.
夫妻吵架是寻常事
Maybe by this chance
也许趁此机会
they will experience some things together.
两人经历一些事情
Their relationship will become more harmonious.
感情更和睦 更甜蜜了呢
Your Majesty. What do you think?
城主 您觉得呢
Qianqian should really gain some experience.
芊芊确实也该历练历练了
Sangqi.
桑奇
Order the Crown Princess
下令着少城主
to suppress bandits in Weimeng Mountain.
前往威猛山剿匪
Young Master Han shall go with her.
韩少君也一同吧
Yes.
是
You're wise, Your Majesty.
城主英明
Do I have to go there?
真的要我去啊
We will appreciate Your Highness' hard work.
那就辛苦少城主
Please go to Weimeng Mountain with Young Master.
携少君走一趟威猛山了
Your Highness. What are you doing?
少城主 你这是
I won't go there.
我不去啊
Why?
为什么
I will go with you.
有我在呢
You don't have to worry about anything.
你什么都不用操心
Think of it as a trip to the mountains and rivers.
就当是去游山玩水
I have no experience in war.
我又没有打仗的经验
Besides, if anything goes wrong,
再说了 要是这差事办砸了
civilians at the foot of Weimeng Mountain will suffer.
岂不是拖累威猛山下的百姓了
Such an important mission should be carried out by Chuchu.
这种大事就应该找楚楚的呀
She should lead the army to suppress bandits.
本来就应该她率军剿匪
Then she would win a great fame.
一战成名的
It seems that Her Highness
我看你们少城主
just wants to handle official documents with Minister Pei.
就是想跟裴司学一起批公文
Don't talk nonsense, even though it is true.
瞎说什么大实话呢
It seems that Your Highness only cares about Minister Pei.
看来少城主心里只有裴司学
Weimeng Mountain is far away.
威猛山山高路远
Aren't you afraid that I will meet some lady on the road
就不怕韩某在路上结识哪家小姐
and will not come back?
不回来了
Do you think you are capable of that?
就凭你
I, Chen Xiaoqian,
我 陈小千
got stuck in my screenplay.
卡在自己剧本里
I only have two missions.
只有两个任务
First, survive.
第一 活下来
Second, bring Han Shuo and Chuchu together
第二 撮合韩烁跟楚楚
to wrap up the story.
推动故事到大结局
I think I would not die soon.
现在一时半会儿是死不了了
There is only one thing left.
那就剩下
I can accept the mission to suppress bandits,
让我去剿匪可以
but I need to bring a person with me.
但是我得带一个人
No.
不行
Chuchu.
楚楚
By the order of Her Majesty,
城主有令
all the people in the city shall follow the order of Your Highness.
城中人士 皆凭少城主调遣
Zi Rui. Ask Chuchu to go with us.
梓锐 去请二郡主楚楚一起剿匪
Yes.
是
Good evening, Young Master.
见过公子
You summoned me at late night. What is the matter that is so urgent?
不知公子深夜传唤 所为何事
the Crown Princess will go to Weimeng Mountain to suppress bandits.
少城主前往威猛山剿匪
Han Shuo will go with Her Highness.
韩烁随行左右
Do you think
你觉得
he can take care of Qianqian?
他能照顾好芊芊吗
Do you mean
公子的意思是
that I should go with them?
让小人随行
You grew up in Pei's Mansion
你自幼在裴府长大
and have been an attendant of me for many years.
跟随我多年
You manage affairs of the mansion
替我将府内事务
in an orderly way.
打理得井井有条
You are most thoughtful and considerate.
最为周到体贴
So I only trust you.
我只信得过你
Please don't worry, Young Master.
公子放心
I will stay with Her Highness
小人会伴在少城主左右
and take good care of her.
护她周全的
Wine pots, tea cups, wine...
酒壶茶盏 酒
Zi Rui.
梓锐
Where are my wine pots, tea cups,
我的酒壶茶盏
and the two-flavored hot pot,
还有那个鸳鸯锅
and hot pot seasoning?
还有那个火锅底料呢
I have brought them.
带了呀
Really?
带了
You see.
你看
All is put inside.
都搁这儿了嘛
Cover it.
盖上
OK. One more thing.
对了 还有那个
Twenty sets of underclothes,
内衣二十套
twenty sets of garments,
外衣二十套
three mantles,
还有披风斗篷三件
and my favorite
还有我平时最喜欢的
jewelry and food.
首饰啊 吃食啊什么的
All should be brought with us.
这些都是要带的
All is ready. You see.
带了 你看
The boxes are all full.
箱子里能装的 都装了
They are full.
满满的
We are supposed to suppress bandits.
你说 咱们去剿匪
We are not moving house.
又不是去搬家
You nearly have emptied Yueli Mansion.
你快把月璃府搬空了
We should be prepared in case of need.
这叫有备无患
I am here.
有我在
You don't need to worry.
你就不用担心了
It is you who don't need to worry.
你才不用担心呢
During this bandit suppression,
这次剿匪
I will arrange everything
我一定把你跟楚楚
for Chuchu and you.
安排得明明白白的
What are you laughing at?
你笑什么呀
You seem very happy to fight bandits with me.
你跟我一块剿匪这么高兴
Of course.
当然了
I will fight bandits with Young Master and Chuchu.
跟少君 二姐一起剿匪
We are sure to win and return home.
肯定得胜归来
Don't worry.
放心
I won't let you waste a trip.
不会让你白走一趟的
Your Highness.
启禀少城主
Knowing that you'll go to Weimeng Mountain to suppress bandits,
裴司学得知您要前往威猛山剿匪
Minister Pei came to see you off.
特来送行
He arrived with an attendant
他还带了个侍从
and said that he would send him to you.
说要送给少城主您呢
OK.
好啊
No.
不行
He has already arrived.
人都带来了
Shouldn't we see him?
不得见一面啊
Ask them to come in.
叫进来吧
One, three, one, eight,
一三 一八
three, two...
三二
Weimeng Mountain is far away.
威猛山路途遥远
This trip will take two to three months.
这一去就是两三个月
Please don't worry.
你放心吧
I will take care of myself.
我会照顾好自己的
I will accompany Qianqian along the way.
一路上我与芊芊形影不离
There is nothing for you to worry about.
裴司学有什么好不放心的
Why do you want to send an attendant to us?
硬要塞个人进来
Please don't laugh at me.
韩少君说笑了
This attendant
我送的这个人
is delicate and considerate with a good temper.
细腻体贴 性子也好
He serves people
比玄虎城的男子
better than men in Xuanhu City.
更会服侍人
I believe you will also like him.
我相信少君也会喜欢他的
You are so generous.
你倒是大方
Just an attendant.
一个侍从罢了
I am willing to give up him.
我自然舍得
You are willing to give up your attendant,
你舍得你侍从
but I am not willing to give up my wife.
我不舍得我夫人
I will take care of Qianqian.
芊芊由我来照顾
Strange! It feels like a domestic dispute.
奇怪 怎么有种后院失火的感觉
Pei Heng, well...
裴恒 这个
I really appreciate your kindness,
你的心意我就领下了
but I will not accept the attendant.
但是人我就不收了
Because I already have
你看我这儿
Han Shuo, Zi Rui,
有韩烁 有梓锐
and Chuchu.
还有楚楚
Every person has different thoughts.
这人心本来就散
It is not easy to lead such a team.
队伍不好带的
So...
这还是
My name is Su Ziying.
小人苏子婴
Greetings to you, Your Highness.
见过少城主
For the sake of our Young Master's
还请少城主
concern for you,
念在我家公子的关怀之情
would you please accept me?
收下小人
Please allow me to report to him if we are safe and sound from time to time.
允许小人不时向他报个平安
She will not accept you.
她不会收的
Minister Pei.
裴司学
Before you send anything to others,
以后再送别人东西之前
please ask them if they like it. Am I right?
先问问对方喜不喜欢 对吧
Wait a moment.
等一下
What's your name again?
你说你叫什么
My name is Su Ziying.
小人苏子婴
Are you Yingying?
难道你就是 婴婴
How do you know my infant name?
少城主怎知小人乳名
So he is
这就是当初
the new role I added
剧情推进不下去的时候
to push forward the plot.
新加的角色呀
In the end, he'll become the match maker for Chuchu and Han Shuo.
最后还成了楚楚跟韩烁的媒人
I just need a talent like you.
我就是缺你这种人才
Zi Rui.
梓锐
What are you waiting for?
你还愣着干吗
Hurry up and ask others to pack all things up.
赶紧带人去收拾东西
We will depart soon.
跟我一起剿匪去
I was looking for you in wind and rain.
风里雨里
I never expected that you would appear today.
没想到你在这里呀
Let's go.
走吧
Go.
快去吧
Yes.
是
Please take care of him.
照顾好他啊
Young Master.
少君
You used a strategy
您刚用了一招釜底抽薪
to separate Pei Heng from Her Highness,
断了裴司学的念想
so you can bring her with you to suppress bandits.
带着少城主去剿匪
I didn't expect him to take counter measures.
没想到他见招拆招
He just seized this opportunity
用了一出打蛇上棍
and sent a spy to watch us.
还派了个眼线
Why did Her Highness
您说少城主
fall into his trap?
怎么就上了他的套了呢
It seems that I spoiled her too much.
看来是我宠她太过了
She just accepted a man without asking me.
竟然随随便便就收了个男人
But he's just an attendant.
不过是个服侍的
But he is still a man.
那也是个男人